# PAOLO TAGLIANI

Senior Freelance Software Engineer

## **PROFILE**

Software Engineering consultant with strong theoretical skills and a passion for OpenSource software.

More than ten years of experience building mobile and web applications. Working remotely since 2015.

Customer-oriented and structured method of working, focused on quality and maintainability. Highly motivated to work in a team, both comfortable in big companies as in small teams.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

### Linux/FullStack developer **Masterchart**

Jan 2021 - Now

Designed and built a complete access management system for banks, composed of several frontend applications and a custom Linux distribution to power personalized in-site kiosk and queue monitor.

### Linux/FullStack developer 41 North

Mar 2021 - Jun 2021

Built a custom Linux distro (based on RaspiOS) to be installed in custom bartop solutions. The system also includes a backend application that stores and distributes legal ROMs. More details at this link.

### Mobile and Full Stack Software Engineer Codermine

Jan 2020 - Dec 2020

Built products for third-party clients with mobile and web technologies. Lead a small development team: mentored junior developers, introduced DevOps practices, and improved release cycle and automated testing. Some of the products build includes:

- Alarm system configuration app ( link )
- Invoice trading platform (frontend and backend) (link)
- AI-based KPI prediction platform (link)

# Mobile / FullStack Software Engineer

Ago 2019 - Dec 2019

### **Palmabit**

Full-Stack consultant.

- Cirular Economy based delivery service (Link)
- Bluetooth powered chat application (link)

### CONTACT

- 74/0, Tormini Gavardo (BS), Italy
- +39 329 2783809
- pablosproject@gmail.com
- pablosproject.com
  - github.com/pablosproject
- in linkedin.com/in/paolotagliani

# **EDUCATION**

### 2010 - 2013

Master's Degree in **Computer Science** University of Brescia

### 2011 - 2012

Exchange student in **Computer Science** LaSalle Barcelona, Ramon Llull University

### 2006 - 2012

Bachelor's Degree in **Computer Science** University of Brescia

# LANGUAGES

- · Italian (mother tongue)
- · English
- Spanish
- Catalan

# Mobile / Full Stack Software Engineer MobileJazz

Worked remotely as an employee doing consultancy work for US and European clients. I worked as an iOS developer in the mobile team, then moved to backend using Node. JS based technologies and ended in web team doing Angular Frontend work. I was also responsible for DevOps, automation, and custom build solutions in each team I worked in.

Relevant examples of products I worked on:

- IoT custom light control solution ( link , blog post )
- Real-time noise monitoring platform (link)
- · Rehab enhancement platform (link)
- TENS remote control application (link)
- Tinder-like social networking application ( link )

### iOS Developer

May 2013 - Jun 2015

### **TilTap**

Worked as iOS developer in a dedicated team inside a startup incubator. Built several MVP and product for early stage startups.

# **SKILLS**

### **Programming Languages**

Expert: Typescript, Swift, Objective-C/C++
Advanced: C, C++, Javascript, Python

Familiar: Go, Ruby

### DevOps

GitHub Actions, Gitlab CI/CD Pipelines, Travis CI

### **Frameworks**

Cocoa, Cocoa Touch, NodeJS, NestJS, ExpressJS, Angular

### DB

MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB, Elastic Search

#### Other

Docker, docker-compose, Linux administration, AWS services (S3, lambda, IoT, ECS), cloud based server management (Digital Ocean, Linode)

### PROJECTS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- · US Patent Hazard Recognition (Patent US11093747B2), link
- Founder of PragmaMark: first iOS/MacOSX Italian developer conference
- · Mentor at CoderDojo Brescia